<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Society on veridus</title>
    <link>https://veridus.space/tags/society/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Society on veridus</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://veridus.space/tags/society/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why Nairobi Is the Capital of Africa</title>
      <link>https://veridus.space/opinion/nairobi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://veridus.space/opinion/nairobi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;nairobi.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;information noise&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nairobi is not officially the capital of Africa. There is no declaration, no charter, no continental vote that says so. Addis Ababa holds that title on paper, and rightly so. But capitals are not only decided by documents. Some are shaped by movement, energy, and influence. And by that measure, Nairobi has quietly become something more — not by force, not by announcement, but by gravity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One way to see a city’s influence is to watch where people go. Nairobi draws people from all over Africa — students, journalists, artists, activists, freelancers, and dreamers. Some arrive with clear plans. Many arrive unsure of what lies ahead. Most come because Nairobi feels like possibility. People arrive seeking opportunities, connection, and a chance to grow. Writers come to find new stories. Musicians come to collaborate. Entrepreneurs come because the city’s energy inspires action. Nairobi doesn’t promise an easy path, but it gives people a sense that something can happen — that they can create, learn, and contribute. This is what gives Nairobi its pull. It’s not about perfection. It’s about the chance to be part of something bigger, to move, to meet others, and to leave a mark that goes beyond the city itself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
